<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://szopa.org.pl/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://szopa.org.pl/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2022-05-30T12:50:41+02:00</updated><id>https://szopa.org.pl/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Adam Szopa</title><subtitle>I&apos;ll put stuff here. Eventually.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">KDE Goals Retrospective: Wayland</title><link href="https://szopa.org.pl/kde/2022/05/30/KDE-Goals-Retrospective-Wayland.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="KDE Goals Retrospective: Wayland" /><published>2022-05-30T12:45:00+02:00</published><updated>2022-05-30T12:45:00+02:00</updated><id>https://szopa.org.pl/kde/2022/05/30/KDE-Goals-Retrospective-Wayland</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://szopa.org.pl/kde/2022/05/30/KDE-Goals-Retrospective-Wayland.html">&lt;p&gt;Continuig the series from &lt;a href=&quot;https://szopa.org.pl/kde/2022/05/23/KDE-Goals-Retrospective-Consistency.html&quot;&gt;last week&lt;/a&gt;, here’s another interview with one of our Goal Champions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This time, I’m interviewing Méven - the Goal Champion for Wayland. Check out the interview below:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;embed-container&quot;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/brFv4-HzMBE&quot; width=&quot;700&quot; height=&quot;480&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;
  &lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks to Méven for joining me for this interview. You can check out his blog at: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bivouak.fr/&quot;&gt;http://www.bivouak.fr/&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;See you next week with another retrospective!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="KDE" /><summary type="html">Continuig the series from last week, here’s another interview with one of our Goal Champions.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">KDE Goals Retrospective: Consistency</title><link href="https://szopa.org.pl/kde/2022/05/23/KDE-Goals-Retrospective-Consistency.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="KDE Goals Retrospective: Consistency" /><published>2022-05-23T12:45:00+02:00</published><updated>2022-05-23T12:45:00+02:00</updated><id>https://szopa.org.pl/kde/2022/05/23/KDE-Goals-Retrospective-Consistency</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://szopa.org.pl/kde/2022/05/23/KDE-Goals-Retrospective-Consistency.html">&lt;p&gt;As part of the preparation for the new round of KDE Goals (as described &lt;a href=&quot;https://szopa.org.pl/kde/2022/05/16/KDE-Goals-Process.html&quot;&gt;last week&lt;/a&gt;), I’ll be interviewing our Goal Champions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The purpose is to learn what went good, what could’ve gone better and share wisdom to all that are thinking about becoming a new Champion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This week we start with Niccolò Venerandi. Check it out here:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;embed-container&quot;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/JrUY3sgqPLI&quot; width=&quot;700&quot; height=&quot;480&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;
  &lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you Niccolò! You can find him on &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/veggero/&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/c/Niccol%C3%B2Ve&quot;&gt;YouTube&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;See you next week with another retrospective!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="KDE" /><summary type="html">As part of the preparation for the new round of KDE Goals (as described last week), I’ll be interviewing our Goal Champions.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">KDE Goals Process</title><link href="https://szopa.org.pl/kde/2022/05/16/KDE-Goals-Process.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="KDE Goals Process" /><published>2022-05-16T12:20:00+02:00</published><updated>2022-05-16T12:20:00+02:00</updated><id>https://szopa.org.pl/kde/2022/05/16/KDE-Goals-Process</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://szopa.org.pl/kde/2022/05/16/KDE-Goals-Process.html">&lt;p&gt;Hello!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sorry everyone, it has been &lt;em&gt;a while&lt;/em&gt;. Of course, the lack of updates to my blog doesn’t mean that the KDE Goals were also not progressing. On the contrary! Wayland, Consistency and Apps are looking better than ever before.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, I don’t want to talk about the Goals themselves, but rather about the process of selecting new Goals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You see, &lt;a href=&quot;https://akademy.kde.org/2022&quot;&gt;Akademy 2022 has been recently announced&lt;/a&gt;. And because we have a date of the event, it means we can take a look at the &lt;a href=&quot;https://community.kde.org/Goals/Goals_Process&quot;&gt;process&lt;/a&gt; that is described on the community wiki and determine when the new Goals can be created.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/akademy2022logo.png&quot; alt=&quot;Akademy 2022 logo&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The process says, that 15 weeks before the start of Akademy the submission stage begins. Since this year’s Akademy is held October 1-7, looking at my calendar it means that June 17th should be the start date. That’s soon! But don’t worry, that stage lasts 4 weeks, so if you’d like to submit a new Goal for the KDE community, you still have time to think about it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the submission stage, a refinement stage and voting follow. Check the &lt;a href=&quot;https://community.kde.org/Goals/Goals_Process&quot;&gt;wiki page&lt;/a&gt; for details.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’d like to use the remaining time before mid-June to talk about what makes a good KDE Goal, summarize the current ones, and interview with our Champions about tips for those that would like to take their place. Check the blog for updates on all of that!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="KDE" /><summary type="html">Hello!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">KDE Goals Update – June 2021</title><link href="https://szopa.org.pl/kde/2021/06/16/KDE-Goals-June-2021.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="KDE Goals Update – June 2021" /><published>2021-06-16T20:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2021-06-16T20:00:00+02:00</updated><id>https://szopa.org.pl/kde/2021/06/16/KDE-Goals-June-2021</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://szopa.org.pl/kde/2021/06/16/KDE-Goals-June-2021.html">&lt;p&gt;Hello!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://akademy.kde.org/2021&quot;&gt;Akademy&lt;/a&gt; starts in a few days, and the Champions and I will be focusing on that. However, there are still some interesting updates we’d like to share with you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s jump right in!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/akademy2021logo.png&quot; alt=&quot;Akademy 2021 logo&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;wayland&quot;&gt;Wayland&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With every recent Plasma update (and especially the just released &lt;a href=&quot;https://kde.org/announcements/plasma/5/5.22.0/&quot;&gt;version 5.22&lt;/a&gt;) the list of features that are X11 exclusive gets smaller and smaller.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Conversely, many users may not be aware that the opposite is also happening: every day there are more features available on Wayland that cannot be found on X11!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are many resources available describing the security advantages of Wayland over X11, but the ageing protocol has some other shortcomings as well. For example, the last update we highlighted was the recently released &lt;a href=&quot;https://invent.kde.org/plasma/kwin/-/merge_requests/718&quot;&gt;VRR support&lt;/a&gt; in 5.22. Among other things, this enables an important use case for me: it allows each of my connected displays to operate at their highest refresh rate. I have a 144Hz main display, but occasionally I plug in my TV, which works at 60Hz. Because of limitations of X11, for everything to work, my main display needs to be limited to 60Hz when both of them are active. But not any more thanks to Wayland!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While the KDE developers always try to bring new functionalities to all users, the above example shows that sometimes, either due to X11 limitations or for other reasons, feature parity will not be possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For different, but similar reasons, some other features that are Wayland exclusive are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Finding stuff using the Global Menu search &lt;a href=&quot;https://invent.kde.org/plasma/plasma-workspace/-/merge_requests/134&quot;&gt;https://invent.kde.org/plasma/plasma-workspace/-/merge_requests/134&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Setting scroll speed factors for input devices &lt;a href=&quot;https://phabricator.kde.org/D28310&quot;&gt;https://phabricator.kde.org/D28310&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Setting multiple DPIs across different displays&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Automatically setting Notifications to “do not disturb” when screencasting &lt;a href=&quot;https://invent.kde.org/plasma/xdg-desktop-portal-kde/-/merge_requests/33&quot;&gt;https://invent.kde.org/plasma/xdg-desktop-portal-kde/-/merge_requests/33&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Stopping applications currently screencasting &lt;a href=&quot;https://invent.kde.org/plasma/xdg-desktop-portal-kde/-/merge_requests/38&quot;&gt;https://invent.kde.org/plasma/xdg-desktop-portal-kde/-/merge_requests/38&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can be sure that the list of Wayland exclusives will grow and grow as work progresses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Méven and Vlad will have a Wayland Goal talk at Akademy. Check out the details here: &lt;a href=&quot;https://conf.kde.org/event/1/contributions/5/&quot;&gt;https://conf.kde.org/event/1/contributions/5/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;consistency&quot;&gt;Consistency&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you think about consistency, you may think of how different parts of your Plasma desktop should look and behave in a similar way, like scrollbars should all look the same on all windows. Or like when you open a new tab, it should always open in the same place, regardless of the app.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But the KDE developers also think about the bigger picture, like: How can we achieve a consistent experience between your desktop and your phone? Here’s where &lt;a href=&quot;https://develop.kde.org/frameworks/kirigami/&quot;&gt;Kirigami&lt;/a&gt; comes in! It makes sense to have applications like &lt;a href=&quot;https://apps.kde.org/neochat/&quot;&gt;NeoChat&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://invent.kde.org/network/tok&quot;&gt;Tok&lt;/a&gt; on both Plasma desktop and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.plasma-mobile.org/&quot;&gt;Plasma Mobile&lt;/a&gt;, and, thanks to the Kirigami framework, users will feel at home on both form factors. Now I want to see Kirigami apps on a smartwatch!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/neochat_combined.png&quot; alt=&quot;NeoChat desktop and mobile powered by Kirigami&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;NeoChat desktop and mobile powered by Kirigami&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Speaking of Kirigami, there is work being done on a component called “swipenavigator” to increase its - you guessed it - consistency, among other fixes. Details of the rewrite are in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://invent.kde.org/frameworks/kirigami/-/merge_requests/310&quot;&gt;merge request&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do you care about looks? Then you’ll be interested in two MR’s: the first regarding &lt;a href=&quot;https://invent.kde.org/frameworks/plasma-framework/-/merge_requests/270&quot;&gt;better shadows&lt;/a&gt;, and the other is the “Blue Ocean” style for buttons, checkboxes etc. There are some details at &lt;a href=&quot;https://pointieststick.com/2021/06/11/this-week-in-kde-plasma-5-22-arrives-but-i-bet-youll-want-5-23-once-i-show-you-this/&quot;&gt;Nates blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our Consistency Champion Niccolò has a Goal talk during Akademy, so be sure to &lt;a href=&quot;https://conf.kde.org/event/1/contributions/1/&quot;&gt;watch it&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;kde-is-all-about-the-apps&quot;&gt;KDE is All About the Apps&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As announced on the community mailing list and the &lt;em&gt;Goals&lt;/em&gt; matrix room, there was a meeting last Monday to discuss the way forward with the huge list of topics mentioned in the previous update.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the meeting, the conclusion was to start with the topics regarding the different platforms we support, as well as the automation of the build/release process of apps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Taking advantage of the upcoming Akademy, the topics will be discussed during the BoF sessions. Check out the &lt;a href=&quot;https://community.kde.org/Akademy/2021/AllBoF&quot;&gt;schedule&lt;/a&gt; to see when you can attend! Also, don’t miss the “Creating Plasma Mobile apps” BoF!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, like the other Goal Champions, Aleix will have a talk on the first day of Akademy, &lt;a href=&quot;https://conf.kde.org/event/1/contributions/6/&quot;&gt;don’t miss it&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;meta&quot;&gt;Meta&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Right after the three &lt;em&gt;Goal&lt;/em&gt; talks at Akademy, there will be a&lt;a href=&quot;https://conf.kde.org/event/1/contributions/7/&quot;&gt; KDE Goals round table&lt;/a&gt;, a session where Lydia and I will be joined by the Champions to answer community questions regarding the specific goals, and the goal program as a whole.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Later in the event, on Monday June 21st at 18:00 UTC, I will conduct a BoF regarding selecting the next goals! Be sure to join in, if you were thinking about becoming a Champion yourself, or if you’re just curious about the process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;See you there!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/adam_tshirt2021_small.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;This is how I would look like in the Akademy t-shirt, if Akademy was an in-person event this year. And held outside.&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;This is how I would look like in the Akademy t-shirt, if Akademy was an in-person event this year. And held outside.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="KDE" /><summary type="html">Hello!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">KDE Goals Update – May 2021</title><link href="https://szopa.org.pl/kde/2021/05/23/KDE-Goals-May-2021.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="KDE Goals Update – May 2021" /><published>2021-05-23T12:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2021-05-23T12:00:00+02:00</updated><id>https://szopa.org.pl/kde/2021/05/23/KDE-Goals-May-2021</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://szopa.org.pl/kde/2021/05/23/KDE-Goals-May-2021.html">&lt;p&gt;Hello! This is the first entry in a hopefully reoccurring series of blog posts about the KDE Goals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The purpose of this series is to provide a frequent update about the Goals, to highlight what cool things are happening.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, our Goal Champions can still create additional content about their goals in any form they want: short blog posts, videos, in-depth articles, etc. This blog will aggregate that content and also give the champions a way to share quick updates without spending too much time blogging.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And with that, let’s take a look at the updates!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;wayland&quot;&gt;Wayland&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Plasma 5.22 is coming, and with that a lot of improvements and fixes to Wayland support. Readers of &lt;a href=&quot;https://pointieststick.com/&quot;&gt;Nate’s blog&lt;/a&gt; have surely seen many of those highlighted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Personally, I’m very excited about variable refresh rate (FreeSync) support being added. I asked Xaver, author of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://invent.kde.org/plasma/kwin/-/merge_requests/718&quot;&gt;merge request&lt;/a&gt; (and the &lt;a href=&quot;https://invent.kde.org/plasma/kwin/-/merge_requests/811&quot;&gt;GPU hot-plug&lt;/a&gt; one!) to write about the new features. Hopefully, we’ll get some juicy details soon!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, you can start testing Plasma 5.22 right now! David has a &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.davidedmundson.co.uk/blog/plasma-5-22-beta-testing-day/&quot;&gt;post about that&lt;/a&gt;. Be sure to report any bugs found and see if the list of &lt;a href=&quot;https://community.kde.org/Plasma/Wayland_Showstoppers&quot;&gt;Wayland showstoppers&lt;/a&gt; needs updating.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;consistency&quot;&gt;Consistency&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Niccolo sent over a full list of recent consistency updates!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1. We are adding a new re-usable component called KHamburgerMenu that will make hamburger menus consistent throughout Plasma. It’s cool because it adapts to your toolbar: if you take an action off it will appear in the hamburger menu, and if you add an action it will disappear from it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://invent.kde.org/system/dolphin/-/merge_requests/168&quot;&gt;https://invent.kde.org/system/dolphin/-/merge_requests/168&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2. Ark now has a welcome screen!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://invent.kde.org/utilities/ark/-/merge_requests/47&quot;&gt;https://invent.kde.org/utilities/ark/-/merge_requests/47&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3. Gwenview sidebar has been made more consistent with our current humane interface guidelines&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://invent.kde.org/graphics/gwenview/-/merge_requests/64&quot;&gt;https://invent.kde.org/graphics/gwenview/-/merge_requests/64&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4. Discover now uses standard cards to display reviews instead of custom component&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://invent.kde.org/plasma/discover/-/merge_requests/80&quot;&gt;https://invent.kde.org/plasma/discover/-/merge_requests/80&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;5. Viewswitcher in libhandy now are more consistent to Plasma style&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://invent.kde.org/plasma/breeze-gtk/-/merge_requests/18&quot;&gt;https://invent.kde.org/plasma/breeze-gtk/-/merge_requests/18&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;6. Calendar has been completely redesigned and now uses Plasma style elements more consistently: the top area, the vertical line like in kickoff, etc&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://invent.kde.org/plasma/plasma-workspace/-/merge_requests/727&quot;&gt;https://invent.kde.org/plasma/plasma-workspace/-/merge_requests/727&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;7. Work in progress: we are bringing the highlight from Plasma everywhere on applications as well! A great step forward for our consistency goal of using the same highlight everywhere.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=MppOSRfFbE8&quot;&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=MppOSRfFbE8&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oof, who knew there’s so much work to do just to stay consistent!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;kde-is-all-about-the-apps&quot;&gt;KDE is All About the Apps&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a different kind of news, Jonathan has stepped down as the Goal Champion. Thank you very much for all the work done to make KDE a better home for apps, Jonathan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Goal’s new champion is &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.proli.net/&quot;&gt;Aleix&lt;/a&gt;. He wants to start by asking the community to discuss a range of topics regarding the Goal. Here’s a list from Aleix:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;platforms
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;linux
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;flatpak&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;appimage&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;snap&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;distros&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;bsd&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;android&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;windows&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;os x&lt;br /&gt;
??? to discuss: ways to reach the platform, our unique selling points there to focus&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;promo
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;website presence&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;business
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;making money for devs&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;fundraising for KDE&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;suites
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;PIM&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Edu&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Calligra&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;developer story&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Plasma
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Plasma &amp;amp; apps
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;which apps should be just considered plasma-specific/oriented? what can we leverage from this specificity?&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;what apps are we lacking?&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Plasma mobile&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Plasma desktop (?)&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;other form factors: TV, tablet, etc&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Tech used
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Kirigami and KDE Apps&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;KXMLGUI and KDE Apps&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m sure we’ll need a couple of meetings to cover all of that! If you’re interested in participating in the discussion of ANY of those topics, please reach out specify which ones. This will help narrow down the focus of the first meeting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;meta&quot;&gt;Meta&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While I’m not actually working on any of the Goals, I do help how I can with the KDE Goals initiative as a whole. This blog is part of that. Additionally, I plan to write a description of the Goal Champion role, since currently we don’t have anything “official”. Let me know if you have ideas about what such a description should include.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="KDE" /><summary type="html">Hello! This is the first entry in a hopefully reoccurring series of blog posts about the KDE Goals.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">KDE Goals – a year lost, a year gained</title><link href="https://szopa.org.pl/kde/2021/01/23/A-Year-Lost-A-Year-Gained.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="KDE Goals – a year lost, a year gained" /><published>2021-01-23T15:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2021-01-23T15:00:00+01:00</updated><id>https://szopa.org.pl/kde/2021/01/23/A-Year-Lost-A-Year-Gained</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://szopa.org.pl/kde/2021/01/23/A-Year-Lost-A-Year-Gained.html">&lt;p&gt;The year 2020 was difficult in many ways, but it also was important for me: I joined KDE e.V. as a consultant in the role of Project Coordinator.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the main focuses of mine was supporting the &lt;a href=&quot;https://kde.org/goals/&quot;&gt;KDE Goals&lt;/a&gt; initiative, which resulted in creating a formalized &lt;a href=&quot;https://community.kde.org/Goals/Goals_Process&quot;&gt;process&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you might know (or read in the process), the KDE Goals are to be replaced roughly every two years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This timebox was selected to balance keeping the Goals fresh, and letting the Goal Champions have enough time to work on the topics with the community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Often, the goals have dedicated &lt;a href=&quot;https://community.kde.org/Sprints&quot;&gt;Sprints&lt;/a&gt;, where community members from all over the world meet up to work together – this not only greatly accelerates the work, but also lets the community create a stronger bond (and is a perfect opportunity to take group photos that the Promo team can use later 🙂 ).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you might guess, the previous year was hardly an ideal one for those kind of events, and even though Virtual Sprints did happen, they can only be a substitute for the in-person ones.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So as the new year started, discussion about a potential extension of the current Goals period began. An extension would mean that instead of starting the process of selecting new Goals this year, we would do that in 2022 instead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This has two main benefits:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The current goals will get more time to finish the work that is
already ongoing and was somewhat hindered by the pandemic. And if
we’re lucky enough, perhaps by this time next year we could even
think about having a in-person event.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The new Goal Champions will start their reign in a (hopefully) more
predictable world, with all of us having a better understanding if
the vaccines will let us travel and meet again. This will help the
Champions set the scope of the Goals.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course there are some considerations to be made. As mentioned before, the process assumes replacing Goals with new ones, so that they reflect the current focus of the community. Extending the Goals forever would resolve in a discrepancy between what the community wants, and what the KDE e.V. is promoting and helping with. However, I hope you agree with me that the current Goals (&lt;a href=&quot;https://community.kde.org/Goals/Wayland&quot;&gt;Wayland&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://community.kde.org/Goals/Consistency&quot;&gt;Consistency&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://community.kde.org/Goals/All_about_the_Apps&quot;&gt;KDE is All About the Apps&lt;/a&gt;) are still very much relevant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The other thing is, Championing can be a demanding task, so our current Champions might feel exhausted with an extra year in focus. The good news is, after talking with Méven, Niccolo and Jonathan I can confirm that they are ready to extend their roles for an additional year. Additionally, I have confirmed with the KDE e.V. Board that they are OK with this extension as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So this brings me to the part, where I can officially announce, that the KDE Goals get an extra year! I hope this will give you more time to &lt;a href=&quot;https://kde.org/goals/&quot;&gt;engage&lt;/a&gt; with the work being done as part of this initiative, and also more time to plan out your Goal proposals for 2022 🙂&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PS. Speaking of engaging in ongoing work, there is a &lt;a href=&quot;https://community.kde.org/Sprints/Wayland/2021Virtual&quot;&gt;Wayland Virtual Sprint&lt;/a&gt; currently active!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="KDE" /><summary type="html">The year 2020 was difficult in many ways, but it also was important for me: I joined KDE e.V. as a consultant in the role of Project Coordinator.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">KDE in app stores</title><link href="https://szopa.org.pl/kde/2020/03/28/KDE-in-app-stores.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="KDE in app stores" /><published>2020-03-28T12:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-03-28T12:00:00+01:00</updated><id>https://szopa.org.pl/kde/2020/03/28/KDE-in-app-stores</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://szopa.org.pl/kde/2020/03/28/KDE-in-app-stores.html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;introduction&quot;&gt;INTRODUCTION&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you use KDE software, there is a good chance you’re on a Linux distribution and you download the software from your distribution’s repositories.
But the fact is you can get KDE software from a number of sources on different platforms. As project coordinator for KDE e.V. helping with &lt;a href=&quot;https://kde.org/goals&quot;&gt;KDE Goals&lt;/a&gt;, I was tasked to look at app download statistics. Join me in my quest to understand how popular KDE apps are in  various app stores.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;android&quot;&gt;ANDROID&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s start  with one of the most popular operating systems in the world, Android.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;google-play&quot;&gt;Google Play&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First we have the Play Store, the default way of downloading apps in the Google ecosystem. You can find all of the KDE published apps under a &lt;a href=&quot;https://play.google.com/store/apps/dev?id=4758894585905287660&quot;&gt;single developer account&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/playstore.png&quot; alt=&quot;KDE on the Google Play Store&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are only seven apps published, but one of them is a very popular indeed: &lt;a href=&quot;https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=org.kde.kdeconnect_tp&quot;&gt;KDE Connect&lt;/a&gt; has over &lt;strong&gt;half a million&lt;/strong&gt; downloads, and a respectable 4,6 rating with almost 15 thousand reviews. If we dig deeper when logged into the developer console, we can see it has over 200 thousand active users.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think that last metric is very important: raw downloads stats are informative, sure - but you can achieve a high download count with a good marketing push even if the app is mediocre. On the other hand, active users are those that installed and decided to keep the app, as Google Play defines “active installs” as those that had the app installed and were online in the last 30 days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are the stats for all available apps:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Name&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Active Installs&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/thead&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;KDE Connect&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;226 679&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;KStars&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;2 015&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;KTuberling&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;658&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;KAlgebra&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;572&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Behaim Globe&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;511&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Kirigami Gallery&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;165&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Klimbgrades&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;92&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;f-droid&quot;&gt;F-Droid&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Google Play store is not the only way one can install apps. You can directly download .apk files and install them manually or you can use a 3rd party store like F-Droid. I’m not sure if there is way to link to all KDE apps available in F-Droid, but you can search for individual apps, like &lt;a href=&quot;https://f-droid.org/en/packages/org.kde.kdeconnect_tp/&quot;&gt;KDE Connect&lt;/a&gt;. There are no stats for downloads or active users on F-Droid.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;windows&quot;&gt;WINDOWS&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wouldn’t expect most Windows users to use an app store to get KDE apps. For many years the normal process when installing new software in Windows was to google the name, find a download link, get the installer and install the application manually.
But Windows does come with an app store of its own now and, of course, KDE has apps available there as well. I couldn’t find a way to link to a single publisher, so the best I could do is a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.microsoft.com/en-gb/search/shop/Apps?q=KDE%20e.V.&quot;&gt;pre-made search link&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have six published applications in this app store. The Windows store has a number of stats available for developers, but I’ll highlight the 30-day “acquisitions” which I believe is comparable to the statistic from Google Play.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Name&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Acquisitions&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/thead&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Kate&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;32 067&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Okular&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;23 811&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Filelight&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;2 992&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Kile&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;2 391&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;KStars&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;1 825&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Elisa&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;945&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We don’t have a single juggernaut this time, the numbers are comparable between the top 2 apps:
Fun observation: KStars has a similar amount of users on both the Google Play Store and the Windows Store.
Not so fun fact: Kate has 61 user reviews, Okular 108. That’s not much compared to the number of users. If you are using a KDE app, consider writing a review!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note: The public listing on the store shows even less reviews, for example only three total reviews for Kate. I’m not sure if this is somehow filtered for me due to location or language.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/kate_msstore.png&quot; alt=&quot;Kate on the Microsoft Store&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I mentioned, the Windows Store is not the primary way of getting KDE apps on Windows. Using the stats available in the Microsoft Partner Center, I can see that Krita alone had reported &lt;strong&gt;millions of installs&lt;/strong&gt;. Other apps like Kdenlive, Kile, Kdevelop and Okular all have at least 200 thousand installs. I’m not sure how to interpret all of that data, but it shows the huge differences of popularity between download methods.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;snapcraft&quot;&gt;SNAPCRAFT&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This distribution independent app store hosts &lt;a href=&quot;https://snapcraft.io/publisher/kde&quot;&gt;96 KDE apps&lt;/a&gt;. To get usage numbers I needed to go into each app manually, go to the metric tab and check the “Weekly active devices”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If there is ever a need to revisit these numbers more often I would spend some time developing something to get the stats in an automated way: the huge amount of apps published and the need for manual accessing each app makes this task very time-consuming.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, here are the top 10 apps:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Name&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Installs&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/thead&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Okular&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;34 862&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Krita&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;33 874&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Kdenlive&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;14 516&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Kolourpaint&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;9 607&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Ark&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;6 928&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Ktorrent&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;6 210&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Kate&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;3 483&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Umbrello&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;3 253&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Ktouch&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;3 186&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;KCalc&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;3 066&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;…&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;All other apps combined&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;48 668&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some observations:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Not visible in the above list is the &lt;strong&gt;huge amount games&lt;/strong&gt;! Most of them have anywhere from 200 to 1000 active users. Perhaps they’re good candidates to include in the other app stores?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Elisa and Kile are both available in the Windows Store but not in the Snap Store. I think that’s a missed opportunity.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Some of the least popular packages are Kdevelop, Calligra, Filelight and Kontact. I think it shows that users of those apps either had them preinstalled on their systems or are predominantly looking for them elsewhere.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/kmines.png&quot; alt=&quot;Kmines screenshot&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Can you beat me at Kmines?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;flathub&quot;&gt;FLATHUB&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This other Linux focused app store has 38 KDE apps available. Similarly to the Windows Store, instead of a publisher listing I can offer a &lt;a href=&quot;https://flathub.org/apps/search/kde&quot;&gt;search link&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This store needed the most amount of work from me. Compared to the other stores, there is no “developer account” I could login into. Instead, all of the stats are available &lt;a href=&quot;https://flathub.org/stats/&quot;&gt;in the open&lt;/a&gt;. I like this approach, but unfortunately the data provided is just raw download numbers that need some treatment to be useful.  I used this &lt;a href=&quot;https://gitlab.com/ahayzen/flathub-api-stats-generator&quot;&gt;python tool&lt;/a&gt; to help me with that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The other issue is understanding the numbers. The other app stores all provide some sort of metric that shows the active users in a time frame, but here I only have downloads. This means that if I try to look at the number of downloads of an app in the last 30 days, but the app had 1 or more updates in that time, it would duplicate the number of users (once for the initial download and then again for each update downloaded).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To make some sense of all of this, I decided to look at the number of downloads since the last app update - assuming that active users keep apps up to date. This would more or less show the current usage. Again, I needed to do this work manually (check the last update date and ask for stats from then to now, for every app) and if this is not a one-off exercise a better way needs to be developed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fortunately for me, most of the apps were updated on March 5th so I could query for many of them at the same time. Since I gathered the stats on March 28th, it should be enough time for most users to download the update and thus show up as a active user.
There are however some problems still: some apps show no update date at all (perhaps they were truly never updated) or had updates a long time ago (querying from that date would show huge cumulative download numbers). The other issue is that Krita was updated on March 25th, which could result in smaller reported number of downloads as users haven’t updated yet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Based on all of these assumptions, here is my compiled list of top 10 apps that were updated on March 5th:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Name&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Downloads or updates between March 5-28&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/thead&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Kalzium&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;38 959&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Kgeography&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;38 561&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Knavalbattle&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;36 107&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Kbounce&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;31 467&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Kbruch&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;31 282&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Kblocks&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;30 971&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Kdenlive&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;30 843&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;kwordquiz&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;30 169&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Ksudoku&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;30 133&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Kgoldrunner&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;30 038&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now this is quite different from all other app stores. The app composition is different (3 educational apps, 6 games) and the download numbers are quite similar in the top 10. This means that either my method is flawed, or flathub users are very different compared to those of other app stores.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For completion, some other stats:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Name&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Downloads&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/thead&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Gcompris March 5-28&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;22 363&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Gcompris since last update 2019-12-01&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;67 961&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Kdenlive March 5-28&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;30 843&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Kdenlive since last update 2020-02-11&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;54 484&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;conclusions&quot;&gt;CONCLUSIONS&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What did I learn after going through all of this data? While perhaps not the most popular way of acquiring KDE software, app stores still serve hundreds of thousands of users. This number grow a lot if &lt;strong&gt;more apps become published on all of the stores&lt;/strong&gt; and the existing listings get some more love with &lt;strong&gt;reviews, better descriptions and screenshots&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Direct file downloads from repositories or mirrors dwarf the app store download numbers, but the stats from those are not collected for privacy reasons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, a successful app store listing is something we can show the world and say “look here, this is a popular KDE app, check it out and maybe check out the others”.
If you’d like to assist with promoting KDE apps, join us in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://matrix.to/#/#kde-all-about-apps:kde.org&quot;&gt;matrix channel&lt;/a&gt; for the &lt;a href=&quot;https://community.kde.org/Goals/All_about_the_Apps&quot;&gt;apps goal&lt;/a&gt; to help out!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;ps&quot;&gt;PS&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some apps have their own listings on app stores like &lt;a href=&quot;https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=net.gcompris.full&quot;&gt;Gcompris on the Play Store&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://store.steampowered.com/app/280680/Krita/&quot;&gt;Krita on Steam&lt;/a&gt;. I did not include those in my stats.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="KDE" /><summary type="html">INTRODUCTION</summary></entry></feed>